Hi, and welcome to this course.
My name is Maximilian Schwarzmüller,
and I will be your instructor in this course.
Now, this course is about NextJS, a framework for ReactJS.
And that might sound strange,
because ReactJS itself already is a JavaScript library,
but over the next lectures, I will explain
what exactly NextJS is,
and why using it could be a good idea.
Now, I can already say that learning it
is a good idea though, because NextJS is super popular,
and it does make building React apps,
large scale React apps but also small React apps,
way easier, because it will give you
solutions for common problems,
which you have to solve over and over again.
And which you'll face in basically
any React project you might be working on.
Therefore, NextJS is amazing,
it is super popular, and in this course
you're going to learn it from the ground up, step by step.
You don't need to know anything
about NextJS to get started,
and you will get all the theory,
the behind the scenes knowledge,
small demos and examples,
and all the bigger projects in this course to ensure
that by the end of the course, you know how to use NextJS,
You know why you use it, what its core features are,
and you will be able to build your own NextJS project
once you're finished with this course.
Now, to see what's in the course, just continue
because I got an entire lecture where I walk you
through the course, and the content of this course,
and of course all that will look at the course curriculum.
This course is packed with knowledge,
and therefore, let's not waste any time,
and let's dive right in,
and let's start with the most important question first.
What exactly is NextJS and
why is using it maybe a good idea?