Now NextJS has more amazing features,
but the last key feature,
which I want to point out here,
is the feature, which is most important
for me labeling NextJS a full stack framework.
Because NextJS also makes it easy
for us as a developer to add backend code
to our react project.
So to build a full stack react project,
where we don't just have the client side code
maybe with service side pre rendering,
but where we also have standalone backend code,
that for example, works with the file system
or reaches out to a database.
With NextJS it's very easy to add
our own backend API into our react project
using NodeJS code.
So we can easily add such code to our Next react apps
when using NextJS.
And that allows us to add code for storing data
to a database or to files,
getting data from there, adding authentication
and all off that.
That's easy to add with NextJS,
we can stay in one project,
we have to know some NodeJS code forded arguably,
but we would have to know that anyways
when we build our own backend,
and then we don't have to build a
standalone REST API project,
but instead we can work on one project,
our Next project, and add all the client's side code,
our react user interface,
and also blend in our backend API code.
That's why NextJS is amazing.
And these are all the core features
I wanted to point out here,
and which we're of course going to learn about
in depth in this course,
and even more than that