Now, we are going to dive super deep
into NextJS throughout this entire course.
Nonetheless, I think it's also pretty nice
to get our hands dirty now already
and to at least explore how a NextJS app works and behaves.
And for this, in this project, which we created,
in this terminal navigated into this project folder,
we can now run npm run dev.
This runs one of the built-in scripts,
which we find here in the package.json file
and npm run dev spins up our development server.
That is a built-in server,
which serves our NextJS pages and the overall application.
It will watch our code
and whenever we save changes to files,
it will automatically reload and update the pages we see
in the browser and it will, in general,
give us a great development experience.
Later, once we're ready to deploy our application,
we're going to run npm run build
to build it for production
to produce an optimized output for deployment
and npm start later then to start this optimized server
because we are working with a real server here,
a Node.js-based server,
since we need that page pre-rendering,
which happens on the server.
But that is already a little bit too much right now.
We are going to dive into that throughout the course
and we are going to learn how to deploy and so on.
And therefore right now,
let's use this dev script
and spin up that development server.
Now, this will then serve this Next application
by default on localhost:3000
as you see in the output down there.
And therefore, you can visit localhost:3000
and you should see something like this.
The exact starting screen could change over time
but it should be something like this
and if you are using my attached snapshot,
you will definitely see this.
Now, what we see on this screen
is actually the result of this index.js file
in the pages folder.
In there, we have a regular React component,
a functional component,
which returns JSX just as we know it from React
but this component here is actually now pre-rendered
and hence, if we view the page source here
in localhost:3000, we find all that content,
which we see on the screen, all that text and so on,
here in the HTML Markup
because this page was pre-rendered
because I did mention that this would be one
of the key features offered by NextJS,
this built-in page pre-rendering,
which we don't have in standard React apps.
So out of the box, we got this
and we can now start working on this project here
or on this page.
And since it is a regular React component,
we can do whatever we can do with React components.
Manage state, render different JSX content
for different states and so on.
But since we're going to dive way deeper
into all these core features
and how we build a NextJS application
with multiple pages and with other React components,
since we are going to dive into all of that,
I will keep this first example very simple
and I will simple clear all the content we have
in this main div here,
all that content, I'll clear it
so that only the div is left
and get rid of this import,
which we don't fully understand yet
but which we will reintroduce later.
And then here in this div,
I'll just add a h1 tag
where I say Hello Next World!
And if we now save this,
the save is picked up,
the dev server updates the page
and we now see this on the screen.
And again, if we view the page source,
we also find this text content here
in the source code so that pre-rendering still works out
of the box.
And that's our first NextJS application,
our first NextJS project.
Arguably not too exciting
but we are going to dive way deeper into NextJS
in the next course sections now.