Now, before we dive
into all those NextJS features
and learn them in depth,
I wanna give you a general overview
of what you can expect from this course
and which content will be in this course.
Of course, also simply go through the curriculum,
which you can see to see what's included in the course
and when you're going to learn what.
But in general, you could say that this course
has three main types of content,
three main content blocks.
We have the basics and foundation block,
which is about all these key features you have to know
when working with NextJS
and where I will introduce those key features
with theory and small examples.
We then also dive into many more advanced concepts
throughout this course,
the concepts which you will need
for your real apps you're building,
for the production-ready apps you're building.
And we'll also have summary content.
So summaries and refreshers,
which are there to save your time
to allow you to quickly summarize
what you learned or to fill gaps, which you might have,
for example, related to React.
Now, in the course modules
that make up this basics and foundation block,
and that's important, by the way.
These blocks are not the course sections
but the categories you could group
those course sections into.
We will have more course sections
than what you will see on this slide.
Here I'm just outlining the main concepts
and categories of content you will learn.
So in this basics and foundation block of content,
you will, for example, learn about file-based routing.
We will have a course section on that.
We are, of course, also going to take a very close look
at page pre-rendering, Server-side Rendering
and fetching data for page pre-rendering.
So preparing and fetching data on the server side
instead of on the client side.
And when to use which approach
because it turns out that we will have different approaches
and different solutions here.
We will also explore how we can combine NextJS features
and NextJS pages with standard React features,
standard React components
and features like context and refs
and everything that makes up React.
And you'll see
that it is very straightforward and every easy.
Nonetheless, we're going to take a look at that as well.
And we are also going to explore API routes
and how we can build fullstack applications with NextJS.
So these are all the core concepts
which we'll explore in depth throughout this course.
But then we're also going to dive into advanced concepts.
We are going to explore
optimization opportunities, for example.
How we can set page metadata.
How we can optimize images
so that we serve small images and load them lazily.
Things like that.
We are going to look behind the scenes
and explore some theory.
In this course, you're not just going to learn how
to do something but also why
and what happens behind the scenes.
We are, of course, also exploring deployment
and configuring our app for deployment,
different ways of building a NextJS application
and I will show you a detailed deployment example
from A to Z where we, at the end,
have our NextJS project up and running
on a production server.
In this course, we are also going
to explore authentication
and how you can add authentication
to your NextJS project
because it turns out that it works a bit differently
than in standard React apps,
that it's easier than in standard React apps
and you're going to learn what's easier
and how it works in this course.
And then regarding those summaries and refreshers,
as I said, they are there to save you time
and fill gaps because for example,
this course includes a full ReactJS refresher module.
Actually, that will be the next module
after this course section.
And you can, of course, skip that ReactJS refresher
if you already know React,
if you have no gaps and if you're ready
to dive into NextJS.
But if it has been some time
since you last worked with React,
if you especially have no experience
or not enough experience with functional components
and React hooks,
or if you only have basic React knowledge in general,
then this ReactJS refresher module is there for you
to ensure that we're all on the same page.
So definitely go through that next module in that case.
If you already have a solid understanding of ReactJS,
if you know functional components and React hooks,
then you can skip it.
And at the end of the course,
you will also find a NextJS summary module,
which summarizes all those key features again
and which, therefore, ensures
that if you're coming back to this course
in a couple of months or even years,
you've got a quick way
of going through all these key features again
without having to go through the entire course again.
And even if you just finished the course,
that summary module can be very nice
for quickly wrapping the course
and again, making sure that you fully understood
all those key features
and that you have the best possible preparation
for building your own NextJS projects.
Now, that's the content.
All this content will be taught with theory
and small demos and examples
but we will then also have multiple bigger projects,
more realistic projects
where we also apply what we learned
so that you have both,
small focused examples and the theory
and then the bigger picture
where everything comes together.
And you also, of course, should practice
what you learned.
From time to time throughout this course,
I will challenge you to try out something on your own
but I also challenge you right now
to do this even if I don't tell you to try something
on your own.
Consider pausing the course
and the videos from time to time
and try out the next steps on your own
without looking at my solution first.
So definitely also take a hands-on approach on your own
and apply what you learned in your own projects outside
of this course and also in the bigger course projects
before we then build them together throughout this course.
This will then ensure that you really understand
what you're learning.