[Maximilian Schwarzmüller] Now there is one special thing
about this course
which I wanna highlight.
You got two main options
for going through that course,
for taking that course.
You have the Standard Approach,
which is the approach which I recommend.
There you start at Lecture One
and Section One.
I guess you already did this,
but then you continue
going through this course,
step-by-step, lecture by lecture.
You can skip the ReactJS refresher module
if you don't need it, of course
but if you need to fill some gaps
also go through that course section.
And then at the end of this course,
you have that NextJS summary module,
which I mentioned.
There I will walk you
through all the core features again,
we'll again build
a small mini project again
and you will basically get
a quick overview of what you learned
and of all the core features.
That is a great course section to take,
once you're done with the course,
which is why
it is at the end of the course
to quickly get a quick overview
of the entire core concepts again.
And it's also a great module
to come back to in the future,
if you took the course
a couple of months ago
and you quickly wanna
go through it again
without going through
the entire course again,
which is of course not that short.
And that's the standard approach
which I recommend.
That you simply go through that course
and then take the summary module
as a well, summary module.
But you can also take the Summary Approach
as I'd like to call it.
We could also call it
the Quickstart approach,
which you can go for
if you're in a hurry.
If you have limited time.
If you wanna learn
the essence of NextJS
as quickly as possible.
For this approach,
you should skip all the Next modules
up to this NextJS summary module.
Only take their ReactJS refresher module
first if you need it.
So take that first
and then the NextJS summary module
if you need to refresh
your ReactJS knowledge,
otherwise skip that
ReactJS refresher module as well
and move forward to
the NextJS summary module.
With that, you will then learn
the essence of NextJS.
The core features that make up NextJS
in the shortest time possible,
you will still get a mini project there,
but of course we're not going to dive
into NextJS as deeply as we do it
in the entire course.
This module is built such that
you can go through it first
without taking the entire course first.
It is built such that
it works stand alone.
And it then summarizes the core concepts
NextJS has to offer,
of course without diving as deeply
into those concepts
and into your different configuration options,
as the rest of this course does.
This course section,
this summary section
will also not include
all the features I cover
in this course in general.
We'll not dive into authentication Deere
or image optimization, for example,
simply because it is a summary module,
an overview module.
This course is as long as it is
for a good reason.
And therefore the summary module
does not replace this course.
But if you just wanna get
a quick overview of NextJS,
if you wanna quickly dive into it
and learn about the core features
and you wanna dive deeply
into the course later,
you can go for this summary approach
and go through this summary module first
and then possibly come back
to the entire course
at a later point of time
to go through that as well.
Now, as I mentioned,
my recommended approach
is the left one though.
That is the approach
with which you will get the most
out of this course.
That is the approach
with which you will
really learn NextJS in depth.
But if you're in a hurry,
you can go for the right approach instead.