Now last but not least,
to conclude this first introductory course section,
I wanna make sure that you get the most out of this course.
I wanna ensure that you have a great learning experience
and that you're able to learn NextJS
in the best possible way.
And therefore, I got a couple of recommendations
and tips and tricks for you to ensure that this is the case.
Now, obviously this is a video-based course,
it's a video-on-demand course
and therefore you should take advantage of this.
You should of course watch all those lectures,
preferably in order,
and you should watch them at your pace, set your own speed.
You can use the video player controls to speed me up
or slow me down if I'm going too fast.
It is also perfectly fine and normal to pause and rewind
and to go back to earlier lectures
to ensure that you really understand what I'm explaining.
If something is not clear after watching a video,
watch the video again, that is a normal part of learning.
Repetition is a normal part of learning,
and therefore you should use the fact
that this is a video-on-demand course
and that you can watch videos as often as you want.
But if you wanna get the most out of the course,
don't just watch the videos also code along and practice,
even without me telling you.
I will sometimes challenge you
to try out something on your own,
but I do recommend that you always code along.
That you pause the videos often
and try out the next steps on your own
before we write code together.
Now, of course there will be failures with that approach
but that is how you learn the most,
so definitely consider coding along and practicing.
Now, when you run into errors and problems
try to solve those on your own.
Really, that is the biggest part of learning,
fixing errors and problems on your own.
Don't ask for help immediately,
you will learn way more if you solve problems on your own.
I would even argue that solving problems
is the most important skill as a successful developer.
So therefore use Google, use Stack Overflow,
use resources like this
to find out what could be causing a problem in your code.
And also use my code attachments,
which you find on the last lecture of every module.
My code is attached as a GitHub repository,
in the last lecture of every module,
you will find the links to this GitHub repository
to different branches there,
where the different branches represent
the different course sections.
And then in a given branch,
let's say in the authentication branch here,
you can always go to commits here on the right,
and you will see the different code snapshots
which I created when I recorded that course section.
And you can then always click on this button here
to browse this code repository at this point,
and then you'll find my code snapshot
at this point in the course section.
You can then also download it as a zip file
or clone the repository.
And this commit messages here which I left here
should help you find out to which part of a section,
so to which lecture, a specific code snapshot belongs.
If you just watched the lecture where we added log out
and you wanna compare your code
after this lecture with mine,
it's probably this commit which you wanna use.
So that's how you should use my code attachments
when using my code to compare it to yours.
Now, of course there might be problems
which you just can't solve,
where you don't find the reason for the problem.
And in this case, definitely use the fact
that you're in a community of developers,
help each other and learn together.
We got a Discord channel, a link can be found attached
and in an earlier lecture in this course.
We've got a Discord channel which you can join for free
to discuss with fellow developers, share projects,
help each other and of course also we'll discuss matters
that are not related to this course,
it's a general learning oriented Discord channel after all.
And you can of course also use the Q&amp;A Board,
which comes with this course
to post any other problems you might have
and to also help others there.
Because ultimately, helping others,
solving problems on your own,
coding along and watching the videos at your pace,
that is what will ensure
that you will get the most out of this course.